<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" >
<chapter>
	<title>Smart Tasks Components</title>

	<section>
		<title>Components</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="../media/overallStructure.png" align="center" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>
			This is an overview of the different components of smart tasks
			project.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Profiles</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="../media/profiles.png" align="center" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>One of the goals of smart tasks is to improve the development of
			task oriented interfaces. Profiles makes possible the customization
			of the interfaces for different users, tasks, tasks types, etc, which
			give the flexibility to adapt these interfaces to the needs.</para>
		<section>
			<title>Task Lists Profiles</title>
			<para>
				Task lists usually needs to be customized depending of the
				user.
				For example, a simple user may only need to see the Task Name
				and the
				description on the task list interface. But another user, who
				usually
				has many assigned tasks, should also see a column with the
				priority,
				so he can pick up the most urgent one.
		</para>
			<para>
				Smart tasks gives the possibility of defining profiles inside a task
				list implementation. For example, let's see this task list
				configuration file (in next chapters we will look at these files
				deeper):
				<example>
					<title>
						Task List Configuration
				</title>
					<programlisting language="Json"><xi:include
						href="extras/taskList.config.json" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
						parse="text" /></programlisting>
				</example>
			</para>
			<para>In this case, there are two defined users, one that will only
				show the name, and the busy user will also see the priority and
				status.</para>
			<note>
				<title>Task View Profiles</title>
				<para>Analogous to the task list profiles, the task details view and
					tasks form view
					handle profiles, which can be customized to show
					different type
					details depending of the profile. For more details,
					check the Task Views
					chapter.</para>
			</note>
			<note>
				<title>More details?</title>
				<para>For more advanced details, check the Task Lists chapter.
				</para>
			</note>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>WS-HT Client Wrapper</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="../media/wshtclient.png" align="center" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<section>
			<title>Model</title>
			<para>
				Smart Tasks is based on a java model generated from the Web
				Services -
				Human Tasks specification
				so that it covers all the
				semantics of human tasks and its usages.
		</para>

			<note>
				<para>WS-HumanTask,
					https://www.sdn.sap.com/irj/sdn/go/portal/prtroot/docs/library/uuid/a0c9ce4c-ee02-2a10-4b96-cb205464aa02
				</para>
				<para>© 2007 Active Endpoints Inc., Adobe Systems Inc., BEA Systems
					Inc., International
					Business Machines Corporation, Oracle Inc., and
					SAP AG. All rights reserved.
			</para>
			</note>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>Definitions</title>
			<para>Human tasks represents unit of work performed by people and
				allow integration
				people in service oriented systems. A human task
				should have:
  	</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>People. In a human task can be many people performing
						different roles. For example, the role of a business administator
						will be different for the actual performed of the task.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Data. Human Tasks can get input data that will be valuable to
						complete the task, and also produce output</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>Representations of a task</title>
			<para>The WS-HT standard defines to structures to represent a task,
				that will be used depending on the need:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Task Abstract, that is used to provide the summary data of a
						task, which will be shown on a task list</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Task, which contains all the data of a task</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Task Rendering</title>
			<para>To interact with tasks, it is good to have some interfaces to
				coordinate the task executions, giving enough visibility and
				functionality. Some needed interfaces could be:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Task List. An interface where a user can see all the tasks
						that has assigned, where a summary of the task is displayed.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Task details, where the user can check more details
						information of a task, with task input data, status, and more.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Operate the task. It means a way to start, complete, suspend,
						the task. It mean, make the task go through its state until finish
						it.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Task UI APIs</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="../media/taskuiapis.png" align="center" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Smart Tasks offers a set of APIs that will help the users of the
			framework to build its interfaces in an easy and flexible way,
			independent of the human task vendor.</para>
		<para>The services that smart tasks offers right now include:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Task Lists UI Helper, which is the responsible of retrieving
					to the UI, the customized task lists to be shown.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Task Support UI Helper. This service it responsible of giving
					the UI interaction with a single task, also using profiles and
					single task customization. Basically, it offers three services:
				</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Get the task information, to show to the user of the task
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Get the task form, that the user of the task will have to
							fill</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Action flow, of the task, which usually will be used to show
							in the UI the different actions to be taken in a task.</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Persistence And Transactions</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="../media/persistence.png" align="center" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>To be completed.</para>
	</section>


</chapter>