<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE preface PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" >
<preface id="pref-Hibernate_Development_Guide-Preface">


	<title>Preface</title>
	<para>If you read about BPM Systems you probably notice that some of
		the advantages that they propose are:</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Automation of the company processes.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Coordination between human tasks and systems.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Data handling.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Declarative approach of expressing how business works.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Performance metrics.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		When you understand these points you start asking about how your
		applications will look like. 
</para>
	<para>
		One of the biggest abstraction that BPM Systems provide is the
		unified /
		task list based User Interface approach.
</para>
	<para>
		You will notice that most of the current BPM Systems will
		generate for
		you an unified UI that will contain a task list for each
		user role
		inside your company.
		The main idea behind this decision is to
		be able to guide each user into
		his/her dialy tasks.
</para>
	<para>
		We will end up having a main screen that will contain a task list with
		all the task that the current user must work on.\
</para>
	<para>
		Most of the BPM Systems right now allow you to define a Task Form to each
		different task that you define in your business processes. So, if you
		have 1000 processes (definitions, not instances) and each of them
		define two human tasks you will end up defining 2000 different task
		forms.
</para>
	<para>
		Clicking in a Task List entry the user will access to the defined Task Form
		that will allow him/her to work on that specific task.
</para>
	<para>
		The task list will be populated according the process instances that are
		being created by the company.
</para>
	<para>
		Each BPM System provide a way (a set of APIs) to interact with human
		tasks. There is a good standard that define the Human Task Life Cycle
		(WS-HT). 
</para>
	<para>
		This framework do not try to override each specific Human Task API neither
		the Human Task Life Cycle.
</para>
	<para>
		This framework wraps the Human Task APIs created by different vendors to
		provide an unified set of abstractions and User Interface components
		to allow a Rapid Application Development approach.
</para>

	<section>
		<title>Get Involved</title>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Try Smart Tasks and get involved with the code
					<ulink url="http://github.com/Salaboy/smart-tasks" />
					.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Mailing List / Google Groups for Dev and Design:
					<ulink url="http://groups.google.com/group/smart-tasks" />
					.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>

</preface>